People subscribed to the newspaper for they wanted to know what happened-
-And then they saw the ads.
You?
I didn't know that T-liquor was good for so much.
Today when companies want to advertise ... My God, what there are competitors!
There are social media companies, search engines, influencers.
And damn and his aunt, my God ...
The money that went to do journalism-
-and to make media owners happy now go largely to large tech companies-
-When Facebook or Google.
It's Edwin.
- Hello Hello!
Do you already miss us?
Nah.
They think I'm a superstar and want to make a sponsorship collaboration-
Oh, it's Edwin!
- Hello Hello!
How is it going?
It's going superb!
We talk about agreements and sponsors, but ...
Are there any rules?
I have some vague memory of talking about it.
Absolutely.
This is how it says in the rules of the game for journalists:
"Make sure that journalism and advertising cannot be mixed together."
-No you should not receive gifts.
-Just.
This applies to journalists.
One should not receive gifts, presents or other-
-"which makes it possible to question one's role"-
-"As a standalone, independent, independent journalist".
There must be examples of journalists who have done so.
Or?
Yes.
So it is, unfortunately.
But I'm not a journalist.
It's a heavenly talk about journalists!
-But it doesn't advertise.
As a follower one should be able to choose-
-Do not continue reading a post containing advertising-
-To advertising basically has a purpose to influence us.
We have conducted a review of some fifty influencers posts.
We have seen that there is a great risk that there is post-
-Which contains hidden marketing, which is not allowed.
Several of the posts have sometimes had a advertising marker-
-But the marking has not proven to be sufficient.
It may have been too small or hidden.
The important thing in an advertising marking is that it becomes clear to followers-
-Th the influencer has been paid to publish the post-
There are a lot of English expressions in this world.
It is in different ways advertising, and not independent journalism.
It should look like journalism because people are so tired of advertising-
-So that they instead make it look like journalism.
Therefore, maybe everyone does not print this so superbly.
But you must not do so.
Hidden marketing is prohibited.
It should be clear to readers and viewers that it is advertising.
Some influencers have gone there.
Most recently Therése Lindgren-
-With a million followers on Instagram.
She was convicted that she had not clearly noticed enough that it was advertising.
In the new media landscape of influencers and youtubers, etc.-
It's not exactly the same thing as someone shows genuine interest-
-Alt if there are real people who have pressed the Like button.
No, exactly.
Advertisers who want to cooperate with influencers-
-As interested in REACH which is authentic, for real.
They want to reach out to real people.
They may not be completely satisfied-
-If it's some kind of divided shock.
Now then?
Hello!
-Otherwise, we're ready.
I'm safe!
-Oh really?
Oh, congratulations!
-We drive away and pick you up, then.
-Okay!
When we talk about Källkoll it is important to know-
-If a message is genuine or not.